翻译：Iz      Tiogy      红豆包      小布拿拿
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
《开心汉堡店》第五季第二十一集
听我说
Everybody, please!
大家冷静点
Everybody, let's try to settle down.
现在涨租金  得了吧
I mean, a rent hike? Now? Come on!
费舍奥德简直疯掉了
Fischoeder's out of his freaking mind.
要我们怎么办
What are we supposed to do,
把纱线的价格也往上抬么
jack up the price of yarn?
又会闹事的
There'll be riots! Again!
感觉费舍奥德先生
I'm starting to think Mr. Fischoeder
变成了一位只认钱的房东
just became a landlord for the money.
大家能听我说一句吗
Everyone, can I... can I have your attention?
-安静  -矮木桩要发话了
- Silence! - Yeah, tubby's talking!
费舍奥德先生以前也涨过我们的房租
Mr. Fischoeder has raised our rent before,
但这是有历史以来涨得最高的一次
but this new hike is the biggest ever.
我们谁都付不起
None of us can afford it.
除了我  对吧  儿子
Except for me, right, son?
-什么  -当我没说
- What? - Never mind.
我已经告诉费舍奥德先生
I told Mr. Fischoeder
我们今天要去见他
we were coming to see him today,
但他不知道的是
but what he doesn't know is
如果他坚持涨房租
if he goes ahead with this rent hike,
我们就给他来场房租起义
we're gonna give him a rent strike!
好哎  来场什么
Yeah! A what?
房租起义
A rent strike.
意思就是如果费舍奥德先生要涨房租
It means if Mr. Fischoeder tries to raise the rent,
我们就不付租金了
we'll stop paying it.
那会让他抓狂的  鲍鲍
Oh, that might make him mad, Bobby.
是啊  房东最讨厌这种事了
Yeah, landlords hate stuff like that.
我知道  这是我们对付
Exactly. It's the only leverage we have
费舍奥德这样财大气粗的人的唯一方法
against a guy as big as Fischoeder.
你确定要当挑事儿的吗  鲍勃
You sure you want to be the ringleader on this, Bob?
和他单独面谈可能会更好
You know, it could be better to talk to him one-on-one.
他不是我们的朋友  琳  他是房东
He's not our friend, Lin, he's our landlord.
我们得让他知道我们是来真的
We have to show him we mean business.
鲍鲍认真起来了呢
Bobby Business over here.
我喜欢较真的鲍鲍
I like Bobby Business.
好吧  鲍勃  我们参加
Okay, Bob, we're in.
好耶  鲍鲍  你要领导房租起义了
Yay, Bobby, you're going on a rent strike!
好像在演《吉屋出租》[百老汇音乐剧]
Just like in Rent.
《吉屋出租》讲的不是这个吧
I don't think that's what happens in Rent.
咋不是
No, yeah, that's what happens.
换你笑
Now you smile.
闭嘴  给我闭嘴
Stop it, stop it.
我们一定要带孩子吗
Did we really have to bring our kids?
你一定要戴那条领带吗
Did you really have to wear that tie?
这是为了向费舍奥德表明
It's important to show Fischoeder
我们这么做不只是为了自己
that we're not just doing this for ourselves.
有些人是有家室的
Some of us have families.
我很爱孩子
I love kids.
但讽刺的是
Which is ironic,
他们不能到我的店里来
'cause they're not allowed in my store.
因为我开的是一家情趣用品店
I-I run a sex shop, everybody.
-自我介绍一下  我叫赛尔  -变态
- If we haven't met, I'm Sal. - Pervert.
-你好  赛尔  -对
- Hey, Sal. - Yeah.
多谢你来  赛尔
Thanks for coming, Sal.
大家要牢记我们的口号
Remember, everybody, stick to the script.
房租涨价  业主闹架
Rent hike, rent strike.
看呐
Oh, look!
我就知道那是你们
I thought I heard the pitter-patter
的脚步声
of little tenant feet.
大家来一杯以示欢迎的莫吉托酒吧
Everyone, have a welcome mojito!
莫吉托鸡尾酒呢
Wow, mojitos.
进展不错  鲍鲍
This is going good, Bobby.
-来杯莫吉托  鲍勃  -我不要  多谢
- Mojito, Bob? - Not for me, thanks.
胡说  今天这天气正适合喝莫吉托
Oh, nonsense. It's mojito weather.
我不想喝  莫吉托
I don't want a-a mojito.
琳达  来杯莫吉托
Linda, mojito?
-当然  -这就对了
- Sure! C That a girl.
费舍奥德先生  我们有些话要对您讲
Mr. Fischoeder, we've prepared a few words for you.
等一下
Just, um, give me a second.
我先把莫吉托放下
I'm gonna... put the mojito down.
放那儿很安全
Oh, well, that's a safe place to put it.
字典里给租金的定义是
The dictionary defines "Rent" as a...
这是草稿
This is an old draft.
跳过这段  接着说
Let me just skip ahead. Here we go.
甘地曾经说过
It was Gandhi who said...
我们就说到这里吧  鲍勃
Let me stop you right there, Bob...
甘地会同意的
Gandhi would want me to.
你们来这里是想告诉我如果我涨租金
You're here to tell me that if I raise the rent,
你们就不再交房租了
you'll have a rent strike.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
每当房客像这样一小拨的聚到一起
Whenever tenants get together in these little clumps,
说出的话都是一样
you come up with the same idea.
没错  如果你涨房租
Well, it's true... if you raise the rent,
我们就不交了
we're, we're gonna strike.
大家说对不对
Right, everyone?
但是  鲍勃  以及  忠实的
Oh, but, Bob, and, uh, loyal, uh...
鲍勃粉  鲍勃党们
Bob-ists? Bob-ites?
随你们怎么称呼自己
Whatever you want to call yourselves.
我来告诉你们其实还有一个办法
I'm here to tell you there's another way.
-还有办法  -是的  伙计们
- Another way? - Yes. Carnies?
-我不明白  -一场水球大战
- I don't get it. - A water balloon fight!
-什么  -我说水球大战
- Excuse me? - I said a water balloon fight.
奇幻码头的劳工纠纷都是这么解决的
It's how we settle worker disputes on the wharf.
再加上即兴说唱大战
Well, that and freestyle rap battles.
你们可以使用我的整个庄园作为场地
You may use the entire grounds of my estate,
从被我无视的花园到后面
from the garden I ignore to the field in the back
那片我扔弃淘汰坐骑的土地
where I dump the old rides.
这事不可能
I don't think that's gonna happen.
如果你被打中  你就出局了
If you get hit, you're out.
也就是说你的房租得涨价
And that means your rent is going up.
-听着  -但是  一直没被打中
- Listen, Mr. Fi... - B-But for the lucky winner
最后幸运胜出的人  租金可以减半
who manages to stay dry, your rent gets cut in half.
这么好
All right!
我可以用这笔钱买好多东西
I could use that money... to buy things.
你们觉得如何
Now, what do you say?
不
N-No.
我们来这里是要团结起来  而不是
We came here to stand together, not...
等一等
Hold on, now.
我们家任何一个人赢了
If any member of my family wins,
我的房租都能减半
my rent goes down?
是的  就像过去一样
Yes. Children flank their parents in battle
上阵父子兵
just like in the good old days.
那带孩子的大人岂不是占优势
Oh, so people with kids have an unfair advantage.
你管那叫优势吗
Would you call that an advantage?
我没事
I'm okay.
费舍奥德先生  我们不会参加你的水球大战
Mr. Fischoeder, we're not doing your water balloon fight.
我们要团结一致  对吗
We're standing together. Right?
游戏规则是这样的
Here's how we're gonna do this.
你们尽可能多的拿水球
You grab as many balloons as you can,
去找隐蔽之处  听到我的信号枪后
find cover, and at the sound of my pistol,
水球战就开始了
start ballooning.
大家都为自己而战吧  上啊
Every man for himself! Go!
吉米  你在干什么
Jimmy, what are you doing?!
我在争取为我的租金减半
I'm getting 50% off my rent!
你别动  鲍勃
Don't move, Bob!
站在我能用水球打到你的地方
Stay where I can balloon ya!
不  不  我们要团结一致
No. No, stand together.
房租涨价  业主闹架
Rent hike means rent strike!
琳达  等等  各位
Linda, wait. Guys!
-泰迪  -我支持你  鲍鲍
- Teddy? - I'm with you, Bobby.
我只是快速地去拿个水球
I'm just gonna get a balloon real quick,
因为别人都有水球
'cause everyone else is getting balloons.
房租涨价
Rent hike means rent...
不
No...!
但信号枪说要
Oh, but the gun says yes.
孩子们  别去碰那些水球
Kids, stay away from the water balloons!
你真行  老爸  你觉得你那样说说
Oh, right, Dad, like you can just tell kids,
小孩就会照做的吗
"Stay away from the water balloons."
抱歉  鲍勃
Sorry, Bob.
租客聚了  又散了
Tenant clump un-clumped.
现在大家都是为自己而战了
Now it's every honky for himself.
大家醒一醒
Everyone, focus.
费舍奥德在利用这游戏挑拨离间
Fischoeder is using this to divide us.
如果我们玩这个游戏
People, if we play his game,
只会有一个赢家  剩下的都是输家
there are many losers and only one winner.
那个赢家会是我
And that winner's gonna be me!
雷吉  不要
Reggie, no.
抱歉  鲍勃
Sorry, Bob.
我一直都被人踩在脚下  这次不会了
I'm always the doormat, but not this time.
我要赢这场游戏  而且...
I'm gonna win this thing and...
真的假的
Come on.
打中你了
Gotcha.
为你报仇了  鲍勃
That was for you, Bob.
天呐
Geez.
我输了吗  我出局了
Am I out? I'm out.
打得好  齐克
Good throw, Zeke.
多谢  小吉
Thanks, J-Ju.
结盟吗
So do we have an alliance?
必须的
Hell yeah.
从此你是风儿我是沙
I'm the Katniss to your Pita Bread.
小的们  抓住他们
Carnies, seize them!
干  干什么  救命
Wha...? What are you...? Help!
我永远不会忘记你的  鲍勃
I'll never forget you, Bob!
他们要被带去哪儿
Where are they taking them?
去败者门廊
To the porch of losers.
一旦被打中  就要去门廊呆着
When you're hit, you go up on the porch
边吃零食  边看完剩下的比赛
and watch the rest of the competition and have snacks.
零食
Snacks.
Snacks?
泰迪
Teddy!
都有啥零食啊
What kind of snacks?
起司   法棍
Cheese and French bread.
小腌菜
Little shrunken pickles.
你可都吃不着了
You're missing out.
哎哟  我好饿啊
Oh, my God, I'm so hungry.
爸  你要注意
Dad, you got to take cover.
你这副低价身躯可承载着高价目标呢
You're a high-value target in a low-value body.
这样  我和吉恩组成突击队
All right, Gene and I will form a strike team
解决掉几个二愣子
and go soak some suckers.
这是唯一一次不想赢的湿身比赛
This is one wet T-shirt contest we don't want to win.
不  你们不许出去
No, kids, you're not doing that.
我要和其他租客谈谈  说服他们回来
You guys stay close while I talk to the tenants
你们呆在一起
and get them back together.
已经走了
And... they're gone.
不要紧的  老爸
Don't worry, Dad.
还有我跟老妈
You still have me and Mom.
我们就像特工一样
We're like the Secret Service, Bob.
我们不会走的
We'll never leave your side.
我真的很想吃点腌菜
I'm just gonna get a few little shrunken pickles.
-妈  别去  -哦  对
- Mom, no. - Oh, right, right, right.
各位  别再犯傻啦
People, you're being dumb!
我也不想说这么重  爱之深  责之切
I'm sorry to be harsh, but it's tough love.
翻译过来就是"我爱你们哦"
"Tough love," Aka "Love."
对吗
Am I right?
我听你的  鲍勃
I'm with you, Bob.
这太疯狂了
This is madness.
谢谢你  赛尔
Yes, thank you, Sal!
我们应该团结起来
We got to stay together,
就像电池和我店里
like batteries and the things I sell at my store
需要电池的东西一样
that need the batteries.
太好了  赛尔  谢谢
Great, Sal. Thanks.
鲍勃又开始集结他的小团体了
Oh, Bob's getting his little club back together.
卖性用品的首先倒戈
Start with the porno guy,
这是常有的事儿
that's what they always say.
这声音从哪来的
Where's that coming from?
另外  如果还需要气球
By the way, if you need more balloons,
可以在花园里找我藏好的篮子
I've hidden buckets around the garden.
提示是  有一棵树可是
Let's just say one of these trees bears
硕果累累啊
big, wet, jiggly fruit.
苹果树
Apple tree!
菠萝  葡萄干树
Pineapple! Raisin tree!
败者门廊上的人不许猜
No guessing from the porch of losers.
看  哈罗德和伊迪丝
Look, it's Harold and Edith.
那树屋比我们家的房子都好
That tree house is nicer than our house.
那树都比我们家的房子好
That tree is nicer than our house.
你攻击伊迪丝  我攻击哈罗德
Okay, you hit Edith, I'll hit Harold,
然后我们爬上去瞅瞅松鼠的豪宅有多壕
then we'll climb up and see how rich squirrels live.
准备好了吗
Ready?
我去  那位"老干妈"扔得还真不赖
Man, that old prune can throw a balloon.
可还不止这些呢
There's more where that came from, baby!
哈罗德  掩护边界
Harold, defend the perimeter!
啥  哦好
Wha...? Oh, all right.
撤退  撤退
Retreat! Retreat!
-鲍勃  -干嘛
- Bob. - What?
我有个想法
I got an idea.
我们可以用我的胸罩当投球器
We can use my bra as a balloon launcher.
琳达  不  我们不扔气球
Linda, no, we're not throwing balloons.
而且这个想法也不太好
Also, that idea is not good.
我觉得超棒的
I think it's genius.
-才没有超棒  -明明就有
- It's not genius. - Sure, it is!
名副其实的胸器
A bazonga bazooka!
我们要找个安全的地方
Listen, we got to find a protected spot
又不会被扔  又能对其他租客晓之以理
where we can reason with the tenants without getting hit.
老爸  看
Dad, look.
看来胆小鬼鲍勃找到树篱迷宫了
It looks like Bob the rat has found the hedge maze.
他盯着咱们呢
He's watching us.
我们要去别的地方啦
We're going somewhere else!
才不呆在树篱迷宫呢
Not the hedge maze!
别听他的
Don't listen to him!
他就在迷宫里
He's in the hedge maze!
鲍勃  小心脚下
Watch your step, Bob.
我一直怀疑家里的女佣
I have a suspicion our maid
把垃圾倒在那里
has been tossing the garbage in there
本来该倒在路边
instead of walking it to the curb.
说的就是你  因加
You hear that? Inga?
小吉米  还有齐克
Jimmy Jr. And Zeke.
你们先走
You guys keep going.
这两个交给我
I'll take care of these two.
好吧  小心点  蒂娜
All right, but be careful, Tina.
我生来就小心
I was born careful.
还记得么  你当时在场的
Remember? You were there.
真是的  小吉  我们没气球了
Damn, J-Ju. We're out of balloons
在水球大战里没水球  真是最烂的时机
in a balloon fight... worst time to be out of balloons.
-就是啊  传说中的水球篮呢  -小伙儿
- Yeah. Where's that balloon bucket? - Boys.
-蒂娜  -没水球了是吗
- Tina! - No balloons, huh?
我有一个  但你们有两个人
I have one. But there are two of you.
蒂娜  让我们走吧
Tina, girl, just let us go.
是啊  让我们走
Yeah, let us go!
是可以  但我也可以攻击你  齐克
I could. Or I could throw my balloon at you, Zeke...
好让我和小吉米在这
...and spend some time alone with Jimmy Jr.
浪漫又诡异的迷宫里享受二人世界
In this romantic/creepy hedge maze.
那也行
That'd be okay, yeah.
等等  等等
Hold up now, girl. Hold up!
-你晓得我喜欢你的  对不  -啥
- You, uh... you know I like you, right? - What?
我说我喜欢你  很喜欢
I said I like you. A lot.
我被你迷住了  小蒂蒂  真的
I'm up to my butt in it, T-bird. Come on!
小吉根本不把你当回事
Hell, J-Ju takes you for granted.
-齐克  -抱歉了  小吉  这是事实
- Zeke! - Sorry, J-Ju, it's the truth.
蒂娜  你在干嘛
Tina, wh-what are you doing?
我刚还想约你来着呢
I was just about to ask you on a romantic date!
你放气
Bull feces!
好吧  小吉米  如果我同意
Okay, Jimmy Jr., if I agreed to go on a date with you,
你要带我去哪儿约会
where would you take me?
去...
To, uh... to...
杂货店
the drugstore.
齐克  你能胜过杂货店吗
Zeke, can you do better than the drugstore?
-胜过什么  -胜过杂货店
- Do what? - Do better than the drugstore!
带你吃玉米卷  然后去水族馆
Tacos, then to the touch tank at the aquarium.
看八爪鱼  然后再吃玉米卷
Check out the octopuses. Get tacos again.
也许顺便再喝点什么
Maybe wash it down with some-something to drink.
全都是好东西啊  姑娘
All sorts of good stuff, girl.
小吉米  到你了
Jimmy Jr.? Your move.
我...
I-I...
声明一下  我并没有享受这个过程
Just so you guys know, I'm not enjoying this.
虽然压力很大  但你们继续
It's very stressful. But let's keep going.
我们暴露在外了  准备好掩护我了吗孩子们
We're out in the open, kids. Ready to shield Daddy?
-掩护前方  -掩护后方
- Front shield! - Back shield!
很好  很好  我爱你们
Great. Great. I, uh... I love you.
我不知道有没有人能听到
Listen, I don't know if anyone can hear me,
但我们还有机会逆转局面
but we can still turn this around.
我们不能再互相作战了
We just have to stop fighting each other.
咩咩咩咩咩  互相作战
Me, me, me, me, me, me, fighting each other.
吉米
Jimmy.
很抱歉你的计划没能行得通
Hey, uh, sorry this isn't working out for you, pal.
还是有机会的  吉米
Yeah, well, it could still work out, Jimmy.
我说服了赛尔
I convinced Sal to stop playing.
-赛尔  你也在吗  -在
- Oh, Sal, you in there? - Yeah.
你不想房租减半吗
Well, wait, uh, you don't want to win half off your rent?
别听他的  赛尔
Don't listen to him, Sal.
干你们这行的可不容易
Guys in your line of work are hurting.
可不是吗  该死的网络
Are we ever. Damn Internet.
现在只有提供"精品体验"
Nowadays, people only come into a sex shop
人们才愿意来情趣用品店
if you give 'em a "Boutique experience."
要放爵士乐
Jazz music playing.
还得擦地板
They want clean floors now.
太恶心了  可怜的赛尔
Oh, disgusting! Poor Sal.
你真的很需要获胜  对不对
Boy, you really need to win this thing, huh?
-赛尔  你看出他别有用心了吧  -没有
- Sal, you see what he's doing, right? - No.
哎哟  我一不小心掉了个水球
Oops. I, uh, gently dropped a water balloon on the grass,
它朝你滚去了  赛尔
and it's rolling under the hedge to you, Sal.
真是奇怪
That's weird.
扔鲍勃  扔鲍勃
Throw it at Bob. Throw it at Bob.
赛尔  别捡
Don't pick it up, Sal.
孩子们一起来  扔鲍勃
Come on, kids. Throw it at Bob.
扔鲍勃
Throw it at Bob.
-扔鲍勃  -赛尔
- Throw it at Bob! - Sal...
扔鲍勃
Throw it at Bob!
-扔鲍勃  -他要顶不住了
- Throw it at Bob! - Uh-oh, we're losing him.
扔鲍勃
Throw it at Bob!
-扔鲍勃  -赛尔
- Throw it at Bob! - Sal.
不
No...!
抱歉了  鲍勃和琳达
I'm sorry, Bob and Linda!
琳达  你还好吗
Linda, are you okay?
你用脸挡的
You blocked that with your face.
是啊  我整张脸在眼前闪了一下
Yeah. My whole face flashed before my eyes.
你们这些人是怎么了
What is wrong with you people?!
他们没在听的  鲍勃  别管他们了
They're not listening, Bob. So screw 'em.
你必须战斗
You got to fight.
我要去吃点零食了
And I'm gonna have some snacks.
琳  你在做什么
Lin, what are you doing?
给你胸器  好好利用
The bazonga bazooka... use it.
我应该不会用
I... don't think I will.
鲍勃  听清楚
Bob, listen carefully!
每个罩杯里放一个气球
You put a balloon in each cup.
像弹弓一样往后拉
Pull it back like a slingshot.
-别说了我懂了  -往高出瞄准
- No, I get it. - Aim it slightly up!
你不解释我也懂的
It's not that complicated.
我爱你鲍鲍  祝你好运
I love you, Bobby. Good luck!
她是对的
She's right.
去他妈的这些人
Screw these people.
好消息  费舍奥德先生
Good news, Mr. Fischoeder!
我加入你的水球战了
You got me in your balloon fight!
而且我会赢的  你听见了吗
And I'm gonna win it! You hear that?!
大部分听见了
I heard most of it...
我不能完全听懂你的口音
I can't always understand your accent.
我没有口...  我
I don't have an acc... I...
算了
Never mind!
反正我会赢的
Anyway I'm gonna win!
我参战了
I'm playing the game!
这就是你们这些人想要的吗
Is this what you people wanted?
出来吧
Come on out!
我可以提议结盟吗
May I propose an alliance?
-你可以拒绝的  -好样的  鲍勃
- You could've just said no. - Attaboy, Bob!
这不是你的尺寸  老爸
That's the wrong size for you, Dad.
但颜色挺配
But a good color.
是老妈告诉你用她的胸罩
Did Mom tell you to take her bra
作为投球器的吗
and use it as a balloon launcher?
是的  你怎么知道的
Yes. How did you know that?
我和老妈设想过这个场景好多次了
Mom and I have talked through this scenario dozens of times.
你拿着吧  我不是很想要
Take it. I-I don't really want it.
祝我好运  孩子们
Wish me luck, kids!
好的  好运  来吧  吉恩
Yeah, okay, luck! Come on, Gene.
我们回树屋
We're going back to the tree house
整死几个蠢货
to take out a couple of old coots.
我们有超级火力
We've got superior firepower.
有棉垫增加舒适度的哦
Superior and padded for comfort!
你怎么知道何时亲一个女孩最好
How do you know when it's the right time to kiss a girl?
早上  中午  丛林里
At breakfast, in the afternoon, in the jungle,
结婚时  看医生时
when you're married, and at the doctor's.
-回答得好  -问题好难
- Great answer. - Whew, that was tough.
这游戏还要玩多久  蒂娜
how long do we have to play this game, Tina?
直到我决定为止
Until I make my decision.
可这越来越无聊了
Well, it's getting boring!
你刚才就替我做了决定
Maybe you just made my decision for me.
你知道吗
You know what?
我要撤了
I'm gonna back away.
你要是想砸我的话  尽管动手吧
And if you're gonna throw it, go ahead.
别走
Don't walk away.
我没走  我在跳舞
It's not walking. It's dancing.
-是在走  -是往后退的舞步
- It's walking! - It's a backward dancy strut.
别逼我
Don't make me do it!
来吧  来吧  来吧  来吧  来吧
Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it! Do it!
该死  吉米
Damn it, Jimmy!
轮到我了
It's my turn now.
蒂娜
Tina!
你为什么要说那些话  齐克
Why'd you say all that stuff, Zeke?
你为什么要跟蒂娜说我脸动过刀子
Why'd you tell Tina I've had work done?
那不是真的
It's not true!
所以你是说你生来就有那鼻子么
Oh, like you were born with that nose.
生着两瓣完美嘴唇的是你好吗
You're the one with the perfect lips!
你那又是哪儿来的
Where'd you get those?!
我有个主意
Hey, I have an idea.
你朝蒂娜扔
Why don't you throw it at Tina,
我们还是好伙伴
and we'll be friends again.
不  我好像不是很喜欢这个主意
No, I'm not sure I like that idea.
看呐  树篱
Hey, look, a hedge!
拜拜  我觉得我们都是赢家
Bye! I think we were all winners here.
我恐高
I'm afraid of heights!
你才上了一阶
You're on the first step.
从我这看你像只蚂蚁
You look like an ant from here!
你觉得他们为什么那么想爬上去
Why do you think they want to get up there so bad?
要在水球战里占领高地
You want the high ground in a balloon fight.
伊迪丝很清楚这一点  她可是斗过恐龙的人
Edith would know that. She fought the dinosaurs.
快来帮我把老妈的胸罩绑树上
Come on, help me tie Mom's bra to a tree.
然后把我的内裤绑在鸟身上
Then let's tie my underwear to a bird.
给我回梯子上去  哈罗德
Get back on that ladder, Harold.
你没发心脏病
You're not having a heart attack.
-你就从来没发过  -我发过一次啊
- You've never had a heart attack. - I did once.
那是中风
That was a stroke,
说是中风都很勉强  你个巨婴老头
If you could even call it that, you big baby.
发射准备就绪  就看这一击了
Okay, ready for launch. This is it.
要够大力够湿
Let's make "Double D" Stand for doused and dampened.
该死
Damn!
没想到还真能成功
I did not expect that to work.
连军队也会大吃一惊的
Wait till the Army hears about this.
这简直就是我们一直以来梦寐以求的
It's everything we've ever wanted!
这能收到我们的邮件吗
Can we get our mail here?
-树屋邮件  -树屋电缆
- Tree mail! - Tree cable!
你好
Hello?
费力克斯  你住这吗
Felix? Do you live here?
是的  我哥把我从主楼赶出来了
Yes. My brother kicked me out of the main house
因为我有睡眠呼吸中止症和睡眠放屁不止症
because I have sleep apnea, and sleep fartnea.
看  是水球
Look! Balloons!
"有一棵树硕果累累"说的就是这个啊
Of course! "One of these trees bears wet, jiggly fruit."
这么说真奇怪
That is a weird thing to say.
天呐  水球  一起玩吧
Oh, my God, balloons! Let's play!
孩子们
Kids?
-孩子们 -老爸
- Kids?! - Dad?
好嘞你们占领高地了
Good, you got the high ground!
等我的信号
Okay, wait for my signal.
我们要打得他们屁滚尿流
We're gonna pound these punks!
那新来的是谁
Whoa. Who's the new guy?
美国60年代大热歌曲《Up, Up and Away》
原唱The 5th Dimension
*你想乘坐我美丽的气球吗*
*Would you like to ride in my beautiful balloon?
*Would you like to glide in my beautiful balloon? *
*我们可以在星际遨游  你和我*
*We could float among the stars together, you and I *
*我们可以飞翔*
*Oh, we can fly *
*我们可以*
*Yeah, we can... *
是鲍鲍和蒂娜
It's Bobby and Tina!
只剩下贝尔彻和派丝多家的了
It's just the Belchers and the Pestos now.
加油  鲍鲍  交友
Go, Bobby, go!
意大利香肠诶  这是谁做的
salami! Who catered this?
吉米  出来吧  结束了
Jimmy, come out. This ends now!
蒂娜
Tina!
你炸了我的气球
Hey, you broke my balloon!
至少是正大光明地
Well, at least it was fair and square.
从我看不见的背后袭击的
In my back when I wasn't looking.
放弃吧  鲍勃  我比你气球多
Give up, Bob. I've got more balloons than you,
我还有人肉盾牌
and I've got boy shields.
你好  露易丝吉恩蒂娜的爸爸
Hi, Louise and Gene and Tina's Dad!
后盾脖子勒太紧了
Back shield, ease up on my throat!
不好意思
Sorry!
虽然你有人肉盾牌  吉米
You may have boy shields, Jimmy,
但我有一对男女狙击手
but I have boy and girl snipers!
我说
I said...
我有对男女狙击手
I have boy and girl snipers!
这是娃娃和供娃娃玩的树屋
These are dolls and a tree house for the dolls to play in.
小心  拜托
Careful, please.
他们的设计很像古董
They're made to look like antiques.
狙击手  射他
Snipers! Shoot him!
糟糕
Oh, crap.
他们太远了
Oh, they're too far away.
老妈的胸罩没这射程
Mom's bra doesn't have that kind of range.
估计因为老妈也没必要
I guess Mom's never really had
把自己胸部发射太远
to launch her boobs very far.
要不要用这个
Do you want to use this maybe?
太好了  你怎么会有这个
Yeah! Why do you have this?
我就是用这个把脏衣服发射到主楼去的
It's how I send my dirty laundry over to the main house.
装弹  快
Load it up! Quick!
你只打中了我的小孩  蠢货
You only got my kids, idiots!
好吧  鲍勃
All right, Bob...
等等  吻别  吻别
Wait. Good-bye kiss! Good-bye kiss!
天呐  好好好  走走走走
Oh, God. Okay, okay, okay, go, go, go, go!
吃我两招
Let's see if you can dodge this.
马勒戈壁的
Son of a bitch!
-抱歉  老爸  -抱歉
- Sorry, Dad. - Yeah, sorry.
好吧  好吧  淡定  淡定
All right, all right. Easy now, easy now.
鲍勃  怎么了
Bob? What's the problem?
是啊  别磨蹭了  让我死痛快点
Yeah, quit hot-dogging and do it already.
这是最后一个气球了
This is the last balloon.
是是  动手吧  你这爱炫耀的乡巴佬
Yes, yes, yes. Get to it, you grandstanding foreigner.
不  最后一个气球在我手上
No, I have the last balloon.
也就是说由我决定游戏什么时候结束
That means the game doesn't end till I say it does.
你们都得听我的
You all have to listen to me!
我们本来是要联手作战的  但是
We were gonna work together, but no!
你们非要玩这愚蠢的游戏
You wanted to play this stupid game,
现在都输了吧
and now you all lose!
真N瑟
Oh, someone's a sore winner.
是我太蠢才会以为大家联手
What made me think people coming together
就能达到目标
could accomplish anything?
一群乌合之众
People are the worst!
还联什么手
Coming together is the worst!
-你说完了没  -没有
- Are you finished yet? - No!
只要这气球还在我手上  你们就得听我说话
As long as I have this balloon, you will hear me!
我就要说话  我去
I will be heard! Damn it.
就算是打成平手了吧  这样如何
Well, let's call that a tie. How about this?
-新游戏  大家都去攻击鲍勃  -啥
- New game. Everybody get Bob. - What?
没错  每用气球砸中鲍勃一次
That's right. Each time anyone hits Bob with a balloon,
就能减免50块的租金  鲍勃加50
they get $50 off their rent, and, uh, Bob gets $50 added.
什么  那我要怎样才算赢
What?! How do I win?
你...坚持到日落就行了
You have to... last until sundown.
那时就是游戏就结束的时候
That's when the game ends.
我和因加就该去看《疯狂追车》节目了
And Inga and I watch World's Craziest Car Chases.
大家准备好了吗
Ready, everyone?
等等  不不不不
Wait! No, no, no, no, no!
鲍勃  你有10秒钟的逃跑时间
Bob, you have ten seconds to run.
十  九  八  七  六  一
Ten, nine, eight, six, one.
开始
Go!
救命啊
Help!
不准攻击我的鲍鲍
Leave Bob alone!
他们想这样玩么
This is how they want to play it?
费力克斯
Felix,
你还有脏衣服吗
do you have any more dirty clothes?
-你要多脏的  -震撼我吧
- How dirty we talking? - Wow me.
三角裤送你们
I'll try to keep this briefs.
brief 也有"简短"的意思  这句也是演讲人的口头禅
相当于"我简单说两句"
快跑  鲍勃  快跑
Go, Bob! Go!
我在这边找找
I'm gonna look over here!
我得藏起来
Oh, I got to hide.
-你在哪儿呢  -给你准备了气球哦
- Where are you? - Got a balloon for you.
看来老爸还真有可能赢呢
Dad might just make it through this thing.
马上就快日落了
It's almost sundown.
It's almost sundown?
可是人家没带晚上用的面霜诶
I didn't bring my evening face cream.
你们觉得老爸藏哪儿去了
Where do you think Dad is hiding?
刚那只猪是放屁了吗
And did that pig just fart?
嗨  老爸  你放屁了
Hi, Dad. You farted.
是板凳的声音  快走开
It was the seat. Go away!
要我们加入你  没问题
Get in the pig with you? You got it.
不行  你们这样会引人注意的
No, you guys are gonna draw attention.
我可以赢这游戏的
I can win this thing
只要我再躲个20分钟
if I just lay low for another 20 minutes.
你的意思是说我们应该让自己舒服点咯
So you're saying we better get comfortable?
别别别别
No, no, no, no!
鲍勃  是你吧  兄弟
Bob? You over there, buddy?
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
我得跑了
I have to make a run for it.
老爸  跑步向来不是你的长项
Dad, running's not your thing.
你有没有什么主意
Do you have a plan
是只要一直站着就可以的
that involves standing around all the time?
你说得对  老爸行动确实不太敏捷
You're right. Dad can't move very well.
我谢谢你  蒂娜
Thanks, Tina.
但也许我们可以帮他移动
But maybe we can move Dad.
再使点儿劲
Push harder!
就这样
Yes.
很好  这办法不错
That's great! That could work!
-他在那上面  -快去抓他
- He's over there! - Get him!
鲍勃  我天  天呐
Bob? Oh, God. Oh, God.
走开  你们这些疯子
Back off, you maniacs!
别靠近我的鲍鲍
Leave my Bobby alone!
闪开  琳达
Step aside, Linda.
你来推我啊  雷吉
Make me, Reggie!
来啊  三明治大叔  来跳舞啊
Come on, sandwich man, you want to dance?!
退后  上面那头猪是我们父亲
Get back! That pig up there is our father!
我们老爸在那里面
And our dad's in there!
我们跑过来就是为了朝鲍勃扔气球的
We didn't come this far to not throw balloons at Bob.
麻烦请让开
Move, please.
得  好啊
Okay. You know what? Fine.
你们想减免房租是吧  行啊
You want to win money off your rent? Be my guest.
-琳达  -都结束了鲍勃  准备好被砸吧
- Linda? - It's over, Bob. You're getting ballooned.
你们一共有多少个气球  50  100
What do you got, 50 balloons? A hundred?
太多了
That sounds high.
我们一分钱租金也不用交了
Our rent's gonna be nuts.
因为我们会倒闭  全家去住纸箱
We'll go out of business, live in a box.
你们几个孩子要去工厂打工
You kids are gonna have to work in factories.
我要去C+C音乐工厂[美国音乐组合]
I want to work at C&C Music Factory!
琳达  你在做什么
Linda, what are you doing?
闭嘴  鲍勃
Zip it, Bob!
这一切都是你自找的
You had it coming after everything you did.
是你把大家集合到一起  为他们着想
You brought everyone together, looked out for 'em,
捍卫正义
stood up for what's right.
我知道你卖什么药了
Oh, I see what you're doing.
动手吧  把这家人
Go ahead, destroy everything
一手建立的一切都毁掉吧
this family's worked for.
太好了  我来得正好
Oh, goodie! I'm just in time.
看来鲍勃要被砸了呢
Looks like Bob is about to be ballooned.
必须击中目标哦  不中就不减钱
Direct hits only, people. No splash, no cash.
手法太烂了
Horrible aim.
你们这是怎么了
What's wrong with you people?
看来大家手脚都不怎么灵便
Must be a case of mass butterfingers.
我们要和鲍勃站在一起
We're standing with Bob.
没错  就像过去一样  但这次是真的
Yeah, just like before, but this time for real.
你说呢  吉米
Right, Jimmy?
我还是想朝鲍勃扔气球来着
Ah, I wanted to throw a balloon at Bob.
算了  我过会儿再朝他扔点别的
It's fine. I'll throw something at him later.
肉球啥的
Maybe a meatball.
谢谢你们
Thanks, everyone.
房租涨价  业主闹架
Rent hike, rent strike!
我懂了  就因为我是地主
Oh, I get it. Just because I'm a landlord,
穿西装  戴眼罩
and I wear a white suit and an eye patch,
涨你们房租  开着车四处游荡
and I raise your rent and ride around
朝你们扔爆竹  我就成坏人了
and throw firecrackers at you, I'm the bad guy.
地主也有烦恼的好吗
Well, landlords have problems.
地主也是有烦恼的
Landlords have problems.
再见了
So long.
看到了吗
See?
我的高尔夫车也会和你们的车一样没电
My golf cart loses its charge just like yours.
费舍奥德先生
Oh. Mr. Fischoeder,
我刚意识到一件事
I-I just realized something.
我...能坐这里吗
Is... is it okay if I sit?
大家都看着呢
People are staring.
费舍奥德先生  我应该在召集大家之前
Mr. Fischoeder, before I got all these people together,
先单独来找你
maybe I should have come to you first
和你一对一地谈的
and talked to you one-on-one.
我应该给你一个做好人的机会
I should have given you a chance to be the good guy.
我认识了你这么久  现在才意识到
I've known you a long time, and I just realized now
我也许...伤到你的感情了
I might have... hurt your feelings.
是这样的  鲍勃
Here's the thing, Bob.
我喜欢你  你是好人  算是吧
I like you. You're good people, sort of.
你可以省掉最后那句
You don't have to say "Sort of."
我一直以为自己是那种
And I've always thought of myself
能和群众打成一片的地主
as the kind of landlord you could pal around with.
那种你可以拍他屁股以示友好的人
Someone you could pat on the butt as a sign of affection.
那...我...我可以那样做
That would... I... I would do that.
不  别碰我
No, but don't touch me.
鲍勃  其实我涨房租
The truth is, Bob, I was only raising the rent
只是为了让你注意到我
so you would notice me.
-真的吗  -不是  我是想修个游泳池
- Really? - No. I wanted a pool.
树篱迷宫可没法帮我泡到妞
You can't get chicks with a hedge maze.
那是当然  有道理
Sure. Makes sense.
鲍勃  我改变想法了
Bob, I've reconsidered.
也许我可以等个一两年
Maybe I could postpone the pool
再涨房租修游泳池
and the rent hike for a year or two.
你就不用担心了鲍勃  那时你已经倒闭了
You'll be out of business by then, Bob, don't worry.
谢谢你  费舍奥德先生
Thank you, Mr. Fischoeder.
我知道一个非常好的庆祝方法
I know exactly how we should celebrate.
别砸我的裤子  我穿的白裤子
Don't hit my pants! I'm wearing white.
湿了小鸡鸡会显形的
You'll see the outline of my wiener.
算了  管它呢  来砸我吧
Oh, what the hell. Fire away!
德国反战歌曲
*99个红气球*
*99 red balloons*
*飘在夏日的天空中*
*Floating in the summer sky*
*注意啦  是红色警报*
*Panic bells, it's red alert*
*源于此处  又来自别处*
*Something here from somewhere else *
*战斗机开始轰隆作响*
*The war machine springs to life*
*用它那跃跃欲试的炮口*
*Opens up one eager eye*
*瞄准天空*
*Focusing it on the sky*
*天空飘过99个红气球*
*Where 99 red balloons go by *